Hello, who is it?
Hey Chiharu! I told you not to answer the phone, didn't I?
It's Chiharu! Hello! Hello!
Hello, you've reached the Shigeno residence.
Goro nii-chan!
Kyowa Institute University for Girls
Even given the current condition, when we take
the positive law from the ancient times...
I have no idea of what he's talking about...
I hope we'll finish a bit early.
And there aren't any club activities today... I'm so bored.
Really, is there anything you like besides softball?
W-What's wrong with that?
Nothing...
Hmm, a text from Taiga? That's rare.
Note: From Taiga, Announcement for Big Sis! Seems like Shigeno returned. I'll let you know even though you are not interested in guys.
Once Again
Hey, Kaoru! What's up?
Sorry! I'm skipping the next classes!
Honda's back!
Do your best! And don't you dare forget about
your promise about the first autograph!
Yeah!
Oh, crap! I forgot to put it in silent mode!
Yes, hello?
Taiga.
Oh, it's you? What's up?
Uh, about your text... Is it true that Honda's come back?
Yeah, it's true.
Apparently he called Professor Yamada
to tell him that he was back in Japan.
Oh, I see...
Anything else? Did you hear anything about his plans for now?
Well, first, he said he will start doing his solo training again soon,
but he said he'll show his face at the baseball club first
I see...
What's wrong? If you're so interested in what he's
doing, why don't you go directly to his house?
Well, you do want to see him don't you?
So why don't you go right now?
T-That...
Why don't you go and kiss him, huh?
That's not it at all!
Well, well, she's a bit too old to still be
playing the pure and innocent virgin...
Note: Third from top is Shigeno Goro
It's somewhat irritating, but I'll give it a try.
I wonder if he's here.
Ah no, he just came home today...
It's probably a good idea if I just let him be alone with his family.
No, that's no good. I'd better just go home.
Besides, why should I come and meet him?
Oh, it's you Shimizu!
Ah, ma'am! I'm sorry I haven't contacted you for so long.
It's been a while, yes... So how is it going at the University?
Translator's Note: goukons are joint parties between two or more
groups belonging to different universities or companies.
Uh... Yes, well... hm, well I'm really into the softball club and
also into goukon, and of course I don't have any boyfriends.
I-I didn't need that many details, but...
He's here you know. Goro.
He's arrived this morning, so I think he's
still sleeping because of the jet lag.
Oh, I see. Then I'll come another time--
Can you wait a moment?
I think I can get him out of bed and on his
feet if I tell him that you came to see him.
Ah, no! Don't...
That's strange...
I'm sorry, it seems he left without leaving a note.
I wonder where to...
And since he just came back, he doesn't have a cell phone yet.
I'm sorry you had to come for nothing.
It's okay. I'll come again.
But where did he go?
Maybe he went to see Tashiro or Fuji, or even Komori?
Maybe he wanted to meet with Toshiya-kun now that he's a pro?
In any case, he didn't come to see me.
He's not here either.
Well, I suppose it was to be expected, now that
he's a pro, he wouldn't want to come here.
Oh? Is that you, Shimizu?
Komori!
So Honda-kun's back, huh?
Yeah, so I went right over to his place
to meet him, but he wasn't there.
I want to see him, too. He's making
quite the triumphant return, huh?
If he plays in the Majors next year, I'm
sure he'll become a star right away.
Of course that makes me happy, but somehow I feel like
he's getting even bigger and slipping farther away.
Well, then...
Maybe I should go and challenge Gibson... As if...
Oh, by the way,
Shimizu, don't you think the first place Honda would
want to go as soon as he's back in Japan might be...
Honda
See you later dad, I'll come back.
Shimizu!
W-What a coincidence!
Liar! What are you doing here?
Uh... Well... Komori said you might be here and...
Sorry, I realized it was not really polite to interrupt
you while you were paying respect to your father...
Ugly? Well, you're not the most beautiful, but
you shouldn't say that about yourself!
I didn't say that!
Oh, uh... Then... It's all right.
Well since you're here, come and meet my dad!
Are you sure?
Yeah, my dad will like that.
Honda Family
So, are you all right?
I've been following your performance on
the internet and sports magazines.
It looks like you'll be promoted to the Majors next year, right?
Who knows.
The front office guys at the Hornets decided to
postpone my promotion when they heard about how,
I prioritized the Minors championship by pretending to be injured.
So instead, before going to the Majors, I was asked
to participate in the Arizona Fall Season League.
I think I got their attention now...
Somehow I feel like he's getting even
bigger and slipping farther away.
Oh, right!
On my way back, I wanted to come by your place to give you this!
I couldn't think of a really tasteful souvenir to bring you.
That's the ball from the game where
I go my first save with the Bats.
You said you'd like my autograph last summer's festival, right? So...
Thank you.
Wonder how fast I'll get a premium on it?
You want to sell it!?
Ah, what a feast that was!
Man, that was good!
Especially after eating hamburgers and sandwiches
almost every day over there.
Nothing compares to Japanese meals!
What you mean of course is "nothing compares
to your Mom's Japanese meals", right?
Yes that's it. Hey, Shingo, don't leave the tomatoes Mom made you!
She just cut them!
Oh, you're back Goro!
You look healthy!
Pa-Papa!
Papa!
You're hanging in there.
I never thought you would progress this much in just one year...
Well, I was lucky...
And next year, the Majors at last!
Yeah, I'm starting to see Gibson's back now.
Oh yeah, Father...
Who won the Championship this year?
Did Toshiya or Mayumura become regulars?
What? You mean you don't know?
This year, I didn't have much time to pay attention
to the Japanese baseball news...
I see.
You can take a look at the details yourself, on the computer.
Uh? On the computer?
What, don't tell me you can't use one?
What's wrong with that?
Shingo.
Why don't you show your brother how to use the computer?
No problem.
Thanks.
Come on, Goro nii-chan!
Me, too!
Okay, Chiharu you're coming too!
So he didn't have the time, huh?
No wonder he performed that well.
So you just have to input the word you want to look up here.
Wow, that's great! You're a genius, aren't you?
It's just common sense!
Chiharu, let's go downstairs to play.
What about Goro nii-chan?
Oh!
Later!
The first victory for the Tokyo Warriors in two years?
So the Oceans are in last place or something? That's lame!
Mayumura, with an ERA of 2.78 is in the top five of the whole league!
With 11 wins and 8 losses, he's the best of Yokohama!
Which means he got the Rookie of the Year title?
Well, that's not that surprising, I suppose.
What!?
"At the plate, he has a batting average of .312 with 18 home runs.
In defense, after he became the starter last June
because Yatabe withdrew due to an injury,
he's been performing extraordinarily, pulling the team with
incredible strength toward a tremendous turnaround."
Amazing Toshi! No, Mayumura, too!
Wow, I'm so happy!
Hey, Sato...
There's a journalist waiting for an interview in the lobby.
Oh, all right, excuse me.
Uh... Sorry for making you wait.
Oh, it's no problem really, it's my fault for imposing
this interview on you without an appointment.
And after you won the Rookie of the Year award, I thought it would
have gone to your head, and I would be turned away at the door.
Hmm, Toshi?
Have you already forgotten my voice?
Goro!
And that's how I thought I'd come to tell you I was back, and
at the same time see the face of the new Rookie of the Year.
I see. I'm grateful.
Oh, by the way, I got you a little souvenir from the States.
No, those are clearly Japanese sweets...
But, you are amazing, too. I was checking up
on your performance through the internet.
It's just starting now really.
I don't have any guarantee that I'll be promoted to the Majors,
and even if I do, I don't think it'll be easy to stay on the main roster.
He's even eating them.
W-Well, that's true for me, too.
Next year, Yatabe, the starting catcher,
will come back after he's recovered.
The real competition to be a starter will start then.
But to be honest, with the good results I got, I was hoping I might
get selected as a member of the Japanese national team.
The Japanese national team? What's that?
Eh, you don't know?
What is it?
Next spring, the Baseball World Cup
tournament composed of sixteen countries,
will be held in the USA to determine
who's really the best team in the world.
What? A tournament to determine the
best baseball team in the world?
That's right. The members of the delegation
were officially announced yesterday.
Coming from the Majors and the top Japanese players, they
all deserve the honor of being a representative, really.
The only rookie selected was Mayumura.
Mayumura?
I wanted to be selected, too... But, I wasn't.
The American national team was announced, too.
It started with Gibson and then a list of first-class Major Leaguers
Gibson!?
It's a dream tournament that gathers
all the top players in the world.
How exciting would it have been to
be selected for the Japanese team?
The Japanese national team?
It doesn't really concern me for now.
Softball Club
I'm off
Thank you for today!
Bye!
I'm so sorry, Shimi!
My boyfriend caught a cold and now we have
no way of going to that concert tonight.
Wasn't it Asami who invited you in the first place?
Yeah, and I'm greatful but...
I'm giving you my tickets so you can go with somebody else.
What?
With someone? But in such short notice--
Sorry...
A concert?
Yes, you like this band, right?
That's no good. We have our final exams starting next week.
That's why I'm here studying instead of going to practice.
Just as I thought, it's not possible.
Maki and Misaki couldn't go either, even though
I would have been happy going with anyone.
Did you ask Shigeno senpai?
After all, he probably has a lot of free time, right?
Why would I ask him? There's just no way he would go
to a concert, you know he's only interested in baseball!
You're afraid he'll say no.
Not that I really care about your love life, but I'm sure you're
frustrated enough since you've become a university student.
But I can't see why you can't take it easy
and invite him to a simple concert.
I'm telling you he's just not interested! I don't want to bother
him with this invitation just because we're childhood friends--
So, you're content to always be just childhood friends?
If he's refusing to go to a simple concert with you, it's not because
he's not interested in the music, but that he's not interested in you.
If there's no spark, maybe you should try and
direct your efforts towards someone else.
Goro, can you answer?
All right!
Hello?
Oh, it's you, Shimizu?
Oh, a concert?
What, nobody else wants to go?
As I thought, it's not your thing.
If you can't go, just tell me--
Sounds good.
They open the door for ticket holders at six, right?
Was that Shimizu?
Yeah, apparently she suddenly found herself with no
one to go to a concert, so she's asked me if I could.
Since I'm free anyway, I said I would go.
Ah, what am I going to do?! What am I going to wear?!
Uh, this isn't good. Uh...
Hey!
I'm home!
Welcome back!
Hey Goro, are you going somewhere?
Yeah.
He has a date with Shimizu!
It's not what you think!
You're here early today.
Yeah, we've finished this years adjustment for the World Cup, so...
Adjustments for the World Cup?
Father, are you working for the World Cup?
Yeah.
I'm the pitching and head coach for the national team.
I didn't tell you?
No, you didn't!
Then why couldn't you get me or Toshi selected, father?
Hey, don't talk nonsense.
The right to decide who's selected belongs to Coach Sasaki anyway.
Besides you're just a Minor Leaguer,
and as for Sato, the burden of being the catcher
for that team is still a bit too heavy.
Of course, it's not impossible.
There's no rush, you know.
You're still very young, you'll have your chance.
There will be another World Cup in four years.
In four years, huh?
So this is the last time one could fight against
the American team with Gibson on it.
Goro!
Although the odds aren't very high, there's
still a way to be selected for the team.
There will be a practice game during training
camp for the national team next January.
They plan to pick up some of the young pro players who
will play against the delegation during that match.
If you manage to catch Coach Sasaki's
eye with your skills during the game,
then there's a slight chance you might be selected.
And this is because he's a coach who doesn't care about
careers or names, he only wants to bring the best of Japan.
Mifune Station
South Exit
What, there's still a chance to get onto the national team?
Yeah, during that practice match we just have to
perform well enough to appeal to the coach.
And even if we don't get selected, just the chance to face
the best team in history is just too exciting, isn't it?
What's wrong?
Nothing, I was just thinking that you really haven't changed a bit.
I'm in, that sort of chance is too good to pass on. I'll apply, too.
Amd who knows we might be able to form a battery again.
Father!
Toshi said he'd apply to play on the practice game team as well!
Oh, good.
With that, I'm sure we'll be the first battery.
Hey, Goro!
Why are you still here?
What do you mean "huh"?
Weren't you supposed to meet Shimizu at six?
Shimizu? Meeting?
I completely forgot!
Goro, call her first!
It's probably her.
Hello?
Oh, Shimizu, I'm so sorry.
Something came up and I lost track
of time. I was just about to leave.
Oh, I see, you didn't call and I thought maybe
you had an accident or something...
So you just haven't left yet!
I'm sorry! But now that I think of it, if you wait for me
to arrive you'll just miss everything, won't you?
Don't worry about me and just go by
yourself. I'm not worth the trouble.
I understand.
It's my fault, I shouldn't have invited
you on such short notice. I'm sorry.
What, you're not going?
Well yeah, if I leave now I won't make it.
She shouldn't miss the concert just because
she has to wait for me, right?
Taiga, dinner!
All right.
Huh?
What happened sis? It's not even eight
o'clock, what happened with the concert?
You were wrong... It was a mistake to ask a guy like him.
What's wrong? Didn't you go to the concert together?
Did you guys have a fight--
It's gone.
Somehow all the excitement's gone.
It's fine, nothing wrong with staying childhood friends forever.
Cheers.
Oh, Nogoro! It's been a while, how are you?
Well, I'm good.
I'm here about that phone call the other day.
I was thinking about using the field to keep in shape.
Oh yes, of course. That's not a problem.
Besides, there aren't any practices now due to exams.
Thanks!
Ah Nogoro...
While you're at it, could you go and talk to Shimizu?
I'm sure he'd like to talk to his successful upperclassmen.
I'm not sure he'd really like that.
Heh, this brings back good memories;
this field left us badly drained, but we were able to overcome it.
And now you got some more new members.
I hear you're working hard, Captain.
What sorts of results did you get over the summer?
Nothing to speak of really. Clearly we're far from it.
Actually, the only time Seishuu had results
was when you were on the team.
Now, just getting beyond the second round is reason to be greatful.
Senpai.
Yeah?
Did you do something to my sister yesterday?
Huh?
She came back home without going to the concert.
Eh?
And she was really angry for some reason.
So I thought maybe you did something a little too abrupt or--
Are you insane?!
Then why was she so angry when she came back?
Huh, what are you talking about?
Something came up right before the start of the concert and
since I couldn't make it on time, I told her to go without me!
Man, you're the worst.
What?
So you were going to be late, but why didn't you still go?
You can always get in even when the concert has already begun,
but that was beside the point, wasn't it?
Point? What point are you talking about?
She bought tickets because she wanted to see the concert, right?
I was feeling bad about her missing half of it just
because of me, so I did what I did because,
I thought that was the considerate thing to do!
You really don't get it, do you?
Excuse me, my class is about to start.
Hey Taiga!
What don't I understand?
If you're that thick-headed, she'll be disgusted with you.
I suppose it's fine if you have no intention
of ever having anything more than just...
A childhood friendship relationship with my sister.
Really?
Yes, Coach Sasaki of the Japanese National Team insisted,
that you were to be one of the players
selected for the Young Japan team.
Thank you very much! Do you know about the others?
Do you know if Shigeno Goro has been selected as a member?
Shigeno?
Y-Yes, right now he's the pitcher for the Memphis Bats in Triple A.
Ah I see, I don't think he'll be able to make it.
If you're that thick-headed, she'll be disgusted with you.
I suppose it's fine if you have no intention
of ever having anything more than just...
A childhood friendship relationship with my sister.
It's too early to go home.
Keep it coming; next one!
Oops, sorry!
More!
It's getting dark, it's time we pack it up.
Y-Yeah.
I wonder what happened.
The way she's losing herself completely in her training
seems like she's trying to get something off her mind.
Yeah.
Sports sure are comforting.
I feel a lot better.
I'm over it anyway.
Throwing myself into softball suits me well.
A peeping tom!
I'm telling you I'm not a peeping tom, so stop shouting!
Then explain to me what a man is doing here?
Don't you know boys aren't allowed on campus?
I didn't know!
If you don't leave immediately, I'll call the guards.
Will you just shut up! Do you have a
freshman by the name of Shimizu here?
I just came to see her!
Hu, Shimi?
Hey, Shimizu!
They're treating me like I'm some peeping tom...
Please help me out!
Say, is he the so-called boyfriend everyone is talking about?
But that's no good, you know boys aren't allowed inside the school.
Huh, who is this person?
How could a softball girl as zealous as me have a boyfriend anyway?
Call the guards, quick!
Yes!
Hey! Wait a second, I'm innocent!
Damn it!
Hey Shimizu, what are you so angry about?!
If it's about yesterday, I'm here to apol--
Sorry, I did end up peeping...
I'm not really angry.
I know you didn't mean any harm...
I'd say you were probably late because
of some baseball-related business.
That's why I'm not particularly angry that you were late
or that we didn't get to go to the concert together.
It's just that...
Because you meant no harm, it just explained how
different our feelings towards each other really are.
And the reason why you couldn't tell me
you'd come even if you were late,
was because you weren't even a little excited about all this.
But I'm fine now.
I don't mind being as we were before; just good
friends who share a joke once in a while.
Even if I can't have it all, I don't want to lose everything.
I didn't see that coming.
Ever since we were kids, Shimizu's always been a baseball
teammate, a friend, even almost family...
But I've never even once thought of her as a woman.
And yet...
She is a woman.
I'm really sorry, Goro!
I know I got your hopes up saying you
would get in if you just applied,
as it turns out, you won't be able to participate in the game
between the young players and the national team.
I-I did recommend you, but the circumstances have changed and...
Well, the truth is that the only players on that team will--
I see.
Well then, there's nothing to be done about it... I understand.
G-Goro?
He's acting strangely.
How so?
Well see, last night when I told Goro he wouldn't be selected
to the young players' team, he just kept his cool...
He couldn't wait to face the Japanese team before that.
At first I thought he'd be furious,
but instead he just said there's nothing he can do about it.
Now that you mention it, today he suddenly
left without eating breakfast this morning.
Hmm, I suppose from time to time he can be relaxed.
Well, I'm off.
Have a safe trip.
What's happening to me?
I couldn't sleep at all last night.
It was because you weren't even a little excited about all this.
That's not it.
It's just that she's always been like a
friend to me and I never imagined...
Something so embarrassing as a formal
date or just going out with her.
No-go-ro!
What the hell--
What are you daydreaming about?
Hey, are you doing well?
Tashiro... Fuji...
Taiga told us you had returned, and that you would
take it easy and work out here for a while.
Uchiyama and Miyazaki said they couldn't skip their classes.
They're not very fun, are they?!
But they really wanted to see you, and pass on a "hello".
Ah, really?
So, how was it?
What's your impression of baseball as
it's played in the game's homeland?
Well, wherever you are, baseball is baseball you know.
But I suppose I have a good feel for it.
That's exactly what I thought you'd say.
After all, you're the guy who thought of defeating Kaido
when there wasn't even a baseball club in Seishuu.
But still...
Who thought that they would still be using this field.
We didn't go to Koshien, but this place
brings back the best memories.
but, we missed our entrance into the university, though.
Don't blame that on baseball!
We've been checking up on your preformance
in magazines and on the Internet.
You know that everyone's still cheering on Seishuu's old boy.
Speaking of which...
Have you seen Kaoru?
What? Where did that come from?
I bumped into her on the train the other day.
Are you sure?
Yes, I'm fine.
Thank you.
Kaoru!
Oh, it's you Fuji! You scared me.
Coming home from practice?
Yeah.
You're still into softball, I see.
And what's wrong with that?
Well no, it's just that girls your age, instead of a sweaty
and smelly sports try and get dressed up,
to go out on dates with good men.
By the way, would you like to go out with me?
I don't need that.
You don't need it? Do you mean there's a new guy...
Seriously?
It's because in my case, when I sweat chasing the ball,
I can always feel like I'm on a date.
Even someone as slow as you can
understand what that means, right?
Kaoru is still desperately chasing balls to feel even a little closer,
to that baseball nutcase who left so far away.
I'll add just this Shigeno.
Baseball is great and all, but when a girl has these kind of feelings...
A respectable man should answer them properly.
Kaoru is still desperately chasing balls to feel even a little closer,
to that baseball nutcase who left so far away.
Even if I can't have it all, I don't want to lose everything.
Ah, being gloomy won't do me any good!
A man just has to act sometimes.
Good work everyone!
Y-Yes... Hello?
Huh?
T-Tomorrow?
Well there's no practice, so yeah, sure.
All right then, at 10 in front of the entrance?
We're here!
This place is great. They have both an
amusement park and an aquarium!
We're going to have a lot of fun today!
You're too eager.
All right, where do you want to start?
I'm fine with anything...
Well then... Let's start with that?
Ah, that's no good.
I'll wet myself on a roller coaster.
What?
Then how about that one?
I'll get a nose bleed on the spinning one.
So that one is no good either?
Yeah, we'll both wet ourselves.
Then let's go to that one!
Hmm, heights, I'll wet myself on that, too.
Let's go home.
Come on, I was just joking!
Do you know how many times I got through tight
spots with two outs and the bases loaded?
This is nothing in comparison.
Hey, wait a minute!
You weren't joking.
Are you all right?
Yes, I'm fine. That was nothing.
You know me... In pinches with two outs, bases loaded...
Well, how about stopping for lunch?
I brought a Bento box.
Oh?
Did you make all of that?
Yeah...
But are you sure you'll be able to eat in your condition?
I'm fine, I'm fine!
Thanks for the food!
Is it good?
Yeah, great!
What a relief, I'm glad.
Amazing!
Look at that Shimizu! That's a ray, a ray!
Don't you think it looks a little like Komori?
What's so funny?
No, it's just I was thinking there are a bunch of things I don't know.
You mean like the fact that Komori looks like a ray?
No!
I was thinking that the only Honda Goro
I know, is the one on his mound.
This is the Honda that's afraid of roller coasters...
And gets so gleeful visiting the aquarium.
This is the first time I've seen that Honda.
That's what I was thinking.
Ah, that was fun!
I feel so good! It's been such a long
time since I've been to the sea...
Last time was in junior high, maybe.
Forgive me.
Huh?
You were concerned about the strange things I said
last time, and you felt you had to make up for it.
Otherwise, there's just no way you'd ask me out like you did.
But I'm fine now.
Because I like the Honda with nothing but baseball in his head.
However, if one day you start yearning for something
else other than baseball, let me know.
If I'll be free, I'll consider helping you.
Shall we head home?
You dummy.
Do you honestly think,
I'm not sensitive enough to spend a whole day just to
atone for something, for a mere childhood friend?
Maybe...
I just wanted to go out on a normal date with the girl I like.
And my heart's been throbbing today more than any situations
I've had with two outs and bases loaded.
I'm a guy who's so thick, he needs 10 years to notice something...
Are you fine with that?
Yeah.
I'll think about it.
I just wanted to go out on a regular date with the girl I like.
That wasn't a dream, was it?
Honda really professed his love to me, didn't he?
So we...
Hey...
Your panties are showing.
W-What the hell! Don't you knock?!
I did, I did. But you were screaming "AH" or something so...
Here's the CD I borrowed.
Oh.
So, did something good happen or what?
Well... You were of some help in this so I'll tell you.
As a matter of fact...
What, seriously?!
Huh?
Oh, Goro. So you're training normally again?
I thought you may have had some problems with your health.
What are you talking about?
I've always been in good shape!
Never mind that father, what about that practice
game against the Japanese team?
Practice game?
Stop playing dumb!
I'm talking about you getting me on the young players' team.
Huh, what are you talking about?
Don't you remember I told you in your
room that it wasn't possible anymore.
Oh, really?
I was thinking about something completely different at the time...
Are you sure you're all right?
But, wait... Why isn't it possible anymore?
You're the coach, aren't you?!
How difficult can it be to just let me go to a practice game?!
That's enough. Stop it, will you!
The circumstances have changed.
Before training camp, all the clubs were
reluctant to let go of their players.
In order to avoid creating a mess, it was decided
that it will be a gathering of players,
coming from all 12 teams, with each sending two players.
In other words, only professional Japanese players can participate?
What about Toshiya?
Yeah, Sato was chosen without any problems
since he applied in the first place.
I understand you're not happy, but you should let it go.
It will always be like that; nothing will
happen even if it goes through me.
But I guess if you want to participate that much,
you could always replace me at the
camp as a batting practice pitcher!
Of course, that would be volunteering!
Quit joking around!
Why should I be a batting practice pitcher when
I'm one step away from the Majors?!
No... Hold on.
A batting practice pitcher...
Yes, that's it.
Even without playing in that game, that should be enough!
All right, let's do it!
Today's Sport Flash.
Let's start with baseball; this morning Saeki
Kyoshiro came back from the United States.
It's an impressive return for Kyoshiro; his batting average this
season was .397 and he set the single-season record for hits;
a record which he previously held.
He arrived early in order to prepare for next
January's World Cup, in the Japanese team camp.
Hello, Sato speaking.
Oh Toshi, do you have any plans for tomorrow?
If not, what do you think about training together?
Yeah sure, I don't have any other plans anyway.
Oh, sorry by the way, about what
happened with the Japanese national team.
That's going to work out fine actually.
Christmas Eve's coming up, huh?
Speaking of which, how are things going with Shigeno?
What things...?
Quit joking around, you know what I mean.
I'm asking about the developments since he professed his love.
Well I guess there aren't any developments
to speak of, we haven't gone out since then.
I can't believe it, but it's been almost two weeks!
Oh, but we spoke on the phone two or
three times. He finally got a cell phone.
Just two or three times? Is Shigeno that busy?
Busy? Not at all, he's free I think.
I guess it's just that we're both not really used to this yet--
Kaoru!
Are you sure this is going to work?
Is what?
Well, in the beginning it's about constantly being
with each other or talking on the phone.
Well he's not really a chatterbox you know, he's basically
the hardcore athletic type, so it's no surprise that he--
That's no good, Kaoru!
There are tons of couples who start dating because of mutual
attraction and end up splitting because they let little things slip.
Don't be thinking you can relax just because it's
taken 10 years for your love to come to fruition!
Because your passion starts now, understand?
It's busy?
First Itao, now Kyoshiro is back, too!
I can't wait to face them!
Can't wait to face what?
What the hell?!
You're saying you want to participate in training
camp even as a batting practice pitcher?
Yes, isn't that what you advised me to do?
I-Idiot, I was obviously joking about that.
Well sorry, but I'm serious about it now.
Of course, I don't mind paying for it myself,
and I'm sure the training staff won't object.
Wait a minute!
Who's ever heard of a batting practice pitcher
on the active roster that throws 150 km/h?
Don't tell me you're thinking of doing
something that'll make waves again?
Being a batting practice pitcher doesn't matter, if I can
have Kyoshiro or Itao in front of me, it'll be all right.
If I can hold down top-class Major Leaguers like them,
the coach of the Japanese team won't be able to ignore me.
I know it's a little extreme, but that's the only
way I have to show my worth to them, father!
All right then, let's meet at one o'clock in
front of the Sports Center tomorrow...
Huh? My battery is dead.
Well it doesn't matter, I told him everything I needed to say.
We cannot connect to the number you dialed
because it is out of range or turned off.
Is this a little slip up?
And Christmas Eve is the day after tomorrow...
There are tons of couples who start dating because of mutual
attraction and end up splitting because they let little things slip.
All right!
What's wrong all of a sudden, Shimizu?
It's not that sudden, you know. I tried to call
you yesterday but it wouldn't connect.
Sorry about that, the battery ran out and I left it like that.
Geez!
What brings you here?
Uh, are you free today?
Since my break starts today, I thought that maybe if
you were free we could do some shopping together--
Ah, sorry.
I've arranged a training session with Toshi this afternoon.
Fine, then. I'll just go by myself.
Do you want to come with us?
We're just going to do a light workout
in the warm water pool at the gym.
You would like that, wouldn't you?
I knew I should have said no...
It's been a long while since he last saw me
in a bathing suit, and then there's Toshiya.
Hey, you're late Shimizu!
Hello.
We already met each other during out Little
League game, but we were never formally introduced.
My name is Sato Toshiya, nice to meet you.
And I'm Shimizu, I always watch you play on TV.
I'm sorry to barge in your plans like this.
Not at all. Besides aren't I the third wheel here?
Don't worry about that, I wouldn't mind if it was just the two of us!
W-Well since we're going to walk laps in
the pool, and a boring workout session,
you should go over there and do whatever you want.
Excuse me.
What? Even though joke unexpectedly worked well.
You're going to be a batting practice pitcher for the training camp?
Yeah.
If I can hold down the likes of Kyoshiro and Itao,
it'll be enough to prove my worth to the Coach.
But, they're super stars in the Majors... That's so reckless!
Well, I won't know until I try.
And it's my only way to get onto the team anyway.
But before that Toshi,
I think our bodies have loosened up now,
what do you say to a little race?
Ah, damn it!
One more!
Fine, as many as you want!
All right, let's go! And go!
Backstroke!?
Yeah!
Men's Locker Room
That was a good workout!
Really, when you train with someone
else, it's much more encouraging.
Goro.
Huh?
I brought these. What do you say, we
play catch just a little to finish?
It's been a while, huh?
Yeah, ever since Kaido I suppose.
Well, I guess you can sit now.
You're on your time off, and it's not good for your shoulder.
Don't worry!
My shoulder's warmed up enough, and
my body isn't that delicate you know.
Only one pitch, then.
Wow, it's been a long time since I last
saw Honda's pitch from up close.
I admit Kyoshiro or Itao won't be easy.
But Toshi, you have to understand that I didn't
go to America on a sightseeing tour!
I see.
The camp could see a storm coming through next month.
That was awesome! Did you get even faster, Honda?
It's not fast enough, my goal is to reach 170 km/h.
Next year, I will break in as a batting practice
pitcher and will make them recognize my skill.
That's right, it means we won't get to see each other for a while.
Well, maybe taking it easy is good, too.
After all, it's not really his style to be romantic.
Hey Shimizu...
Hmm?
Tomorrow is Christmas Eve, right?
Do you want to go somewhere with me?
Yes!
You suck! You call that a swinging?
Use your hips! Swing with your hips!
No!
This isn't right, this is not a place for Christmas Eve, Honda!
Welcome
It's still chilly here in Okinawa.
For the upcoming baseball World Cup next March,
the players from the Japanese national team are
gathering here for training camp, which will start tomorrow.
Above all, the attention is of course centered
on the Major Leaguers Kyoshiro and Itao.
Both gave up their winter breaks to come
here and train for the World Cup.
Living up to their reputation of world class players,
they're true inspiration for all the Japanese team.
Uh... Genttlemen, thank you all for coming.
I firmly believe that all the members gathered
here have all it takes to take on the world.
During this camp, plase be very
careful with your individual training,
and try not to overexert yourselves.
I wish you all good luck!
Hello there.
Here's the thing, I'm a batting practice
pitcher here but I don't know anyone.
And I feel lonely, would you mind talking to me?
Man you're cold, Mayumura.
It's me!
S-Shigeno?! What are you doing here?
Like I said I'm a batting practice pitcher.
My father, the pitching coach, pulled some
strings and the head coach agreed.
But I could get in trouble if I show my face, hence the disguise.
Are you Mayumura?
Pleasure to meet you, we've heard rumors about
the strong-armed rookie way over in the States.
Kyoshiro!
Let's both do our best as representatives of Japan.
Yes, I hope we will.
Excuse me, you there.
I apologize if I'm mistaken, but aren't
you Shigeno from the Triple A Bats?
Am I that famous? It's really an honor that you know of me.
I was right; yes, I've heard of you.
When a Japanese performs well, even if it's just in the Minors,
you can't help but hear about them, whether you like it or not.
But still, why are you here?
Only players from the national team
have been called here, I believe.
I'm glad you said that, I was wondering what
arrangements I would have to make to get a meeting,
now I can save a great deal of effort.
A meeting?
Ah, thanks. Let's do the rest together.
When you have batting practice, please ask
for me to be your batting practice pitcher.
I'll show you pitches that are much more lively than all
the coaches and batting practice pitchers over there.
T-T-Time!
What are you doing? You're way out of line!
Did you forget I only brought you here
because you promised to behave?
I forgot.
Sorry.
But I'm afraid you won't be able to pitch against me.
What?
Because, I have my own exclusive batting
practice pitcher, and I only train with him.
You''ll have to try your luck with someone else.
I'm afraid you won't be able to pitch against me.
That's strange, usually in that situation I'd have tried
to insist and say something like "come on, please".
The atmosphere, how should I say... He had an aura backed
by total self-confidence, which left me no opening.
Well I guess if there's nothing to be done about Kyoshiro,
I'll have to try to sneak in when Itao starts his batting practice.
Hey.
Are you a batting practice pitcher?
I am, what about it?
Don't just sit there!
There's equipment to put away, pitching
to do. There are plenty of jobs to be done!
Being a batting practice pitcher also includes
doing all sortsof chores. You idiot!
What? Who do you think you are?
I'm Nemoto, batting practice pitcher.
Coach Shigeno has asked me to train and keep an eye on you.
Hey, can't you carry that a little faster?!
Yeah, yeah.
What sort of an answer is that? Use some effort will you!
Yes!
Stop dawdling and put these away right now!
All right, old man.
Who are you calling old?!
Hey, still here? It's going to be dark soon!
Man, he's a pain!
Huh, did you say something?
Nothing, your ears must be playing tricks on you!
You said you asked Kyoshiro for a match yesterday, right?
Don't push your luck because your father is here as coach.
I don't know what you're worth in Triple A,
but surely it's way too early to have such a big mouth...
You punk!
Okay, that's enough old man!
Who do you think you are?! You keep nagging at me...
Do you get your kicks bullying the new guy or what?
Nemoto speaking.
Hey are you even listening, old man?
Ah, all right, I'll be there right away.
Apparently Kyoshiro wants to do some light practice now.
Of course there's no way you'll pitch,
but do you want to see us train?
That means, Kyoshiro's personal batting practice pitcher... Is you?
I'm really sorry Kyoshiro,
but would you mind showing the technique of a top-class
Major Leaguer to that big-headed Minor Leaguer?
He said he wanted to pitch against you and I'd
like to show him how ashamed he should feel.
Yeah, it's fine.
It's my first batting practice this year, I'm not
sure I'll be able to show him anything special.
I'm sure you'll be all right.
Hmm, yeah right, against the dull old man's pitch,
even if it's nice or crap, I'm not going to see anything.
Let's start!
What's so amazing about that?
Everybody can hit a ball that slow.
When you said he was your exclusive practice pitcher
I imagined something mush more impressive,
but these are just pitches from a batting practice pitcher.
This is just a waste of time.
Wait, Shigeno.
You're making fun of Nemoto!
Go on, pitch!
There's no excuse for such words!
Just pitch. I'll prove your pitches are nothing compared to his.
Hurry up and pitch!
Hey, wait a minute! I haven't had time to warm my shoulder up!
Fine, then take 10 balls to warm up. Nemoto
can always pitch after 10 warm up throws.
Well, let me tell you, I warm up my shoulder quickly, too.
Kyoshiro, it's not like you to let yourself
be tricked into a cheap fight like that.
A fight? No, this has nothing to do with a fight.
It's just that I can't forgive his making fun of your work.
Kyoshiro.
Okay, I'm good.
Well, before we begin shall we establish the rules?
Rules?
Let's make it a three turn at-bat.
If you get one or more hits you win,
but if you don't get any hits after three at-bats,
you'll recommend me to the head coach.
Just one hit? You don't lack in self-confidence...
I don't mind. I would have done for even two
hits, but if you say so I guess it's fine.
Well, go on.
Even for a first-class Major Leaguer, a well
controlled 100 mph fastball won't be so easy to hit!
That's a pity, a line drive right back to the pitcher.
That one counts as an out.
Next one, please.
I can't believe it, that was low and inside almost
that looked out of the strike zone...
And in just one swing...
Crap!
That one was clearly over the left fielder, is there
something you don't understand, Shigeno?
You do not have the skills to make fun of Nemoto's pitches.
Maybe you didn't know...
But Nemoto mastered all sorts of pitches,
timing, and mixing of balls and strikes.
He manages to remind me of real game
situations while letting me hit comfortably.
Sure he can't throw 100 mph pitches, but he delivers lively pitches.
Your pitches, however, have no life in them.
My pitches have no life?
I've stopped using machines for years.
The reason is that I realized it was useless to hit back such
lifeless balls no matter how many times I hit them.
Yes, that's it, your pitches are exactly like
the lifeless balls from those machines.
No matter how much you raise your speed or aim at the corners.
Your pitches are just not scary at all!
Hey there.
So I heard you got humiliated by Kyoshiro.
Oh shut up! It's not funny.
Don't worry about it so much.
Your opponent was Kyoshiro. Even amongst Major
Leaguers, he's one of the best batters.
Father...
Maybe I've finally reached the point where even
I have to learn how to throw breaking balls.
A breaking ball, huh?
Yeah.
Last year my goal in the Minors was to master
the control over my 150 km/h fastball.
And it worked; I was able to get my foot
in the Majors' doors. However...
Against a Major Leaguer like Kyoshiro, it didn't work.
He said that even though my pitches are thrown at 150 km/h,
they're just like those delivered by a machine and aren't scary at all.
In reality, he easily crushed them with the sweet spot of his bat.
I disagree.
It's always the same with you; always rushing to an answer.
Kyoshiro is a batter with an average of
nearly .400 in the Majors, you know.
Don't you think it's a bit hasty to change your
style just because you got hit a little?
Besides...
If there was a breaking ball that you
could use, you'd already be using it.
That's right; that's exactly the problem.
Even in the Majors I stressed and tried to use
breaking balls, but with no results to speak of.
I also tried two-seam and four-seam fastballs, even a
cutter, because they're comparatively close to a fastball...
But in terms of control and sharpness, they
were really far from being a usable weapon.
According to the coach's explanation...
My fingertips remember the sensation of
throwing a fastball with a gyroscopic effect,
and that becomes a hindrance when I throw breaking balls.
That's why, if I want to learn anything, it'll have
to be either a forkball or a change-up.
Damn!
When I pitched right-handed, I could throw change-ups.
Why is it so terrible with the left!
So this is where you are, Shigeno.
What are you doing? The control on that was just terrible.
N-Nothing!
Well it doesn't matter, go to the main field.
It looks like Itao is about to do some batting practice.
D-Does that mean I can throw against Itao?
Of course!
N-No, I'm fine you know, but it was so easy for Kyoshiro
to hit me. Right now, it'll just be the same with Itao.
Huh?!
What the hell are you talking about? You're
a batting practice pitcher, aren't you!?
It's your job to let them hit!
Now get going!
Shigeno.
Huh?
Your mistake was to try to hold down Kyoshiro right away.
A pitcher has things to learn from getting hit.
Try to think about that when you are Itao's batting practice pitcher.
Thank you.
Nice batting!
Oh, you're here Goro! Please replace me!
I'm not so young anymore; just 100 balls and I'm already...
Hey! Don't start loosing your temper and trying to
shut him out with 150 km/h pitches, all right?
It's his first session this year, you understand that?
Heh, I know.
Itao of the Titans...
Last year, I was just a spectator in the right field stands.
However...
Now I'm in front of him on the same field, somehow.
I'm fine with getting only fastballs. Could you spread them properly?
Yes, sir.
A pitcher has things to learn from getting hit.
Try to think about that when you are Itao's batting practice pitcher.
Things to learn from getting hit?
What on Earth does that mean?
That's Itao, no doubt.
He smashed it right out of the field on his first swing!
Damn! I hate this; not just throwing while saving
energy, but also getting hit like this.
What is there to learn from that, old man?
Was that in the zone?
Um yeah, just barely.
It was totally in.
Wait a minute...
So that's what Nemoto was talking about.
It is possible that Itao doesn't like pitches to the outside?
All right, one more.
Of course, two in the same spot will get hit...
But, just now it was a pop fly to left field.
All right, let's try throwing on even more extreme trajectories.
If you do your job as a batting practice pitcher, you get to
throw as many times as you like against top class batters.
You can see their tendencies, their strengths, their weaknesses,
and even their physical condition on that day.
There's no other way to get that kind of opportunity, Shigeno.
This is getting annoying, Shigeno.
You've been pitching only extreme trajectories for a while and
I thought that explained why it was getting difficult to hit.
But aren't you increasing speed as well?
Huh? Is that so?
Well it doesn't matter, it's enough for today.
I just wanted to do some light stretching today and suddenly
I have to worry about not letting you destroy my form.
Itao!
Now that we're both warmed up, what do you
say about getting serious for one at-bat?
I'm sorry, Itao!
Hey Goro, you're completely out of line!
For whom do you think this training is for--
Please bare with this to humor a young Triple A player.
A minute, please.
I heard from Coach Shigeno and Kyoshiro, too,
but I see you really are pushing your luck.
However, dreaming about getting onto the national team so much
as to request an assignment of a batting practice pitcher here...
You're not only pushing your luck, you have guts.
All right, if you want to test your strength so badly, you can join
the youth team, which arrives next week here in Okinawa.
Huh, seriously?
Ah, Coach Sasaki!
It's already been decided that the young members were taken from
12 different Japanese ball clubs, giving us two extra players.
I don't mind, the youth team will have a lot of games to play.
It's really not a problem if we get one or two more pitchers.
This way you'll have your chance to face
Itao and Kyoshiro with all your strength.
Yeah! Thank you, boss!
But until then, you have to do your job as batting practice pitcher.
Yeah I will, I will I won't start any more fights!
Well now, I suppose I should have a look at the bullpen.
Hey Shigeno, can you throw for me now?
Uh, oh... Yes!
Coach Sasaki, why did you do that?
It's true, I did ask you to have a look at him once
if the chance presented itself during this camp.
But to be taken care of this much is a more
generous treatment than what I asked for!
The mere fact that he's allowed to participate
in that camp is already quite enough.
I'm not really granting you any special treatment.
See, Kyoshiro recommended him.
He said ,"This one is interesting. How about we let
him join the youth team to see how it goes?"
Apparently, his precious bat broke during a two-pitch duel.
It seems like a waste to leave him as a batting practice pitcher.
Besides, there's no way we'll get our hands on
the World Cup just by using common sense.
I can think of more drastic things to do.
More drastic things?
I see now... It's exactly like what that old man Nemoto was saying.
I feel as if I'm starting to get the hang of all the batters'
tendencies, their favorite spots and the trajectories they don't like.
But the problem remains...
Damn it! It's just no good!
My forkball doesn't fall at all. I have no control
whatsoever over my change-up...
It'll never become something I can use.
I really won't be able to throw them...
A former right-hander can't just start
throwing breaking balls with his left hand.
Sure.
That's the official catcher, Domoto.
Do you want to start with playing catch?
No, that's alright.
You can crouch. I've already warmed
up my shoulder on the main field.
That's...
Woah! They've already started!
Hey! Let me join you!
Hey!
Goro!?
Katori is one of the starting pitchers for the Pheonix.
Karasawa is the sixth batter for Chukyo.
And Yakushiji is the lead-off hitter for the Saitama Jackals.
To be honest, I never thought Katori
and Karasawa would become pros.
How cruel!
He's unbelievable.
I wonder if there's a limit to your indifference.
However...
Kusano, I see your defensive skills are well
appreciated since you're a starter on the Leopards.
Yeah, I guess.
I'm here, too!
If you hear about the ace relief pitcher for the
Arrows, that's me; Akutsu, the Knuckleball pitcher!
Who are you again?
It's me for crying out loud! Why did you only forget about me?!
Hello juniors, I will ask you not to stand
in the way of Sengoku Masato.
When your upperclassman from Kaido, the best slugger in the
history of the Miyagi Grizzlies, is speaking, listen to him!
I must say, I'm surprised to see you join us.
You must have made a strong impression on Itao and Kyoshiro.
Well, not exactly... Somehow Coach Sasaki picked me up.
Coach Sasaki?
Oh yeah, Toshi...
Can you come with me after we're finished here?
Thank you, everyone. We appreciate your
efforts coming here to Okinawa.
Individually, I think you came here to work out and train, mainly the
same way you've been at your respective teams' training camps.
But tomorrow, your game will be
against the Japanese national team.
So what I want you to do is really frame your
mind as if you are going to beat them.
And now, Coach Sasaki has a serious announcement to make.
A serious announcement?
Gentlemen, in order to make history and build the team
that will conquer the world and take the first World Cup,
I am going to get rid of all useless
preconceptions, big names and past achievements.
I personally think it gets in the way.
Moreover, if you win the practice game against
the Japanese national team tomorrow,
Then you all will...
Be the core team to represent Japan.
If we win...
Japanese national team...
Isn't that interesting?
Well, that's only natural.
That's Coach Sasaki for you. I can't help but
get excited after hearing something like that.
All right, let's do it!
Their eyes seem to have lit up.
That's a good thing. It wouldn't be interesting
if they didn't come at us seriously.
Huh, breaking balls?
Yeah, I learned the hard way that I've reached a point
where throwing only fastballs won't get me very far.
All I've been doing for the past week is
working on throwing breaking balls.
I'd like to see if it's something I'll be able to use
by trying it out against you in a one turn at-bat.
Goro throwing breaking balls?
Well, if he adds a breaking ball to his
fastball, he'll be unbeatable for sure.
If he's never thrown them until now, surely it's not because
he didn't want to, but because he simply couldn't.
Here I come.
What sort of pitch does he have in mind?
A fast slider with a hard break?
A slow curve or some sort of change-up?
There isn't a pitch that you could master in one week
that I shouldn't be able to analyze and foul off.
That's one strike, right?
Huh, was there any break on that one?
Come on, you know that was a fastball just now,
I told you I'd try in one full turn at-bat, didn't I?
Oh, so that's what you meant.
That means he intends to use it as his out pitch.
Outside corner fastball... Well, it's a bit boring to hit.
Knowing him, the decisive pitch will be the third one.
Here comes the breaking ball.
That ball just now...
Was a forkball.
Forkball?
But Goro, when you were in high-school, you also threw
one, but it didn't drop that much nor was it that fast.
How did it become like that with just one week of practice?
Well, there's a guy here who taught me the basics.
I can't believe it.
That's really Suguro!
The Japanese pioneer in the Major League; the man who
fights with great will and determination on the mound.
Nice ball!
May I help you? I can't focus on what I'm
doing if you're watching me so closely.
Oh, I'm sorry. I was hoping to get some insight on
the great Suguro's super famous deadly forkball.
Forkball?
I won't throw any today, I'm afraid. It's
my first warm-up session, you know.
Well, I don't mind...
But could you teach me some things on
the grip or point out a few tips later?
The thing is, I'd like to learn how to throw breaking balls somehow.
If I remember correctly, you're Shigeno...
The closer for the Triple A Memphis Bats, right?
Oh yes, you're well informed.
It's best if you don't throw forkballs if you're just
starting to learn how to throw breaking balls.
The forkball requires a specific skill set, and
it's not a pitch that is easily mastered.
Besides, a breaking ball is quite
stressful on your shoulder and elbow.
I've had to have surgery on both of them.
Besides, there aren't that many pitchers in America who throw it.
Well, I don't really care about that.
I'm sure you don't have any regrets
about throwing forkballs, do you?
What the heck are they doing?
Alright then, Shigeno.
With all your strength, try to grab the ball from my hand.
I just have to pull hard enough to get it out, right?
I don't understand the point of something so simple...
Huh? That's strange!
Damn, what the...?
You won't get it.
To throw a good forkball you need your
fingers to have this kind of strength.
Here, try it out for yourself.
Personally, my grip is around 70 kg. I hear Sasamoto
a famous forkball pitcher, has a grip around 80 kg.
In addition to that grip, you have to train your fingers before...
Shigeno... Your fingers sure have some pinching strength.
I'm not sure about my pinching strength, but I have a
70 kg grip in my right hand and a 90 kg in my left hand.
90 kg?
Now that I think of it, it's not that surprising that I can do this.
I broke my shoulder a while back, and I changed
from pitching right-handed to left-handed.
At that time, I was training my left hand like a madman.
Hey Suguro! If we're not going to do
anything, I'll go to batting practice.
All right, I'll help you. You should be
able to learn how to throw a forkball.
No, not only that. You might be able
to throw better forkballs than me.
And since then, Suguro has been teaching me the basics.
I see. So that forkball just now was
a result from training with Suguro.
Nope. He did teach me the basics, but that wasn't Suguro's forkball.
That was a gyro-fork!
Gyro... Fork
I made up the name just for fun.
If all my attempts to throw a forkball up till now were failures...
It's because I was using my arm and wrist
differently from my normal pitching form.
But with the gyro-fork, I can throw using
the same pitching form I normally use.
Oh yeah. Luckily, the one you saw before went well, but
I'm still just getting one out of two to stay on course.
Obviously, a catcher can't catch it like this.
So far now, I can't use it during a game.
N-No...
That's amazing, With such a great break,
I'm sure any batter will swing, even if the pitch is a ball.
You can use it, Goro!
Huh? No, the control is so...
Even if you get some wild pitches, as long
as the catcher can stop them, it'll be find!
I'll catch them!
Toshi...
We'll win the game tomorrow...
With your gyro-fork!
Can you still pitch today?
Of course, I'm not tired at all!
Alright, then let's practice some more.
All right!
When I said that the winner of this match would become
the main representatives of Japan, it wasn't a lie.
If we lose here against the Young team, winning and advancing in
games against the world would just be a dream among dreams.
I won't bother you and talk strategy. I only have one thing to say:
Let's give Japan's greatest weapon,
Editor's Note: Small ball is the strategy of using bunts, stolen bases, and singles to
advance the runner and score runs without relying on extra-base hits or home runs.
small ball...
A thorough polishing!
Yes!
Looks like they don't plan on going easy on us.
Yeah.
Of course.
It's an earnest match.
Yeah, let's win!
Let's win and earn the right to challenge the world!
Play ball!
Strike!
Wow, what a pitcher! That was an amazing pitch!
G-Goro, don't tell me you've never heard of Harada?
Starting off with Japan's ace...
Naturally...
After all, they also want to check to see how well-prepared they are.
Strike!
The difference in strength is evident,
but if we manage to play our own style
of baseball, we'll have a chance.
A safety bunt!
Safe!
Well done, Kusano!
Second batter, third baseman, Yakushiji.
Push on, Yakushiji!
So it's Yakushiji.
Harada's decisive slider is a tough one...
If I take a pitch, I'll be down in the count,
but the runner is Kusano, who has fast legs.
So instead of going with a safe strategy,
I'll bet on his legs...
And be active!
Hit-and-run!?
Out!
Damn... It snuck up on me, eh?
Don't mind, don't mind!
One out and a runner on second. We have a chance!
Third batter, first base, Karasawa.
Ball!
Harada's known to have some difficulties when he starts pitching.
Is it having to deal with runners on his
back that makes him impatient?
Ball!
Foul!
Ball! Ball four!
One out with runners on first and second, huh?
Leave it to me.
With 28 home runs last year, the greatest slugger
in the history of the Miyagi Grizzlies...
The fourth batter, Sengoku Masato, will decide it all.
Uh... I'm sorry, but Sengoku, you're the fifth batter.
Go for it, Toshi! Get the runners home for us!
A chance in the first inning.
If we can grab even one run here, we'll
be able to take control of the game!
Nice one!
Out!
What an arm!
Leading off the bottom of the first inning for the All Japan team,
the first batter and right fielder, Kyoshiro.
Come on, Katori!
"Japanese representative" means nothing! Just shut them out!
"Just shut them out," huh?
Yeah...
Let's do that!
Strike!
Good, it's cutting well.
Strike two!
Yes! We've got this!
Hey, hey! Just because there are two strikes doesn't mean
you can let your guard down around the opponent.
What are you saying?
Don't forget that with the count to his favor,
Katori has his high-speed slider.
And I know full well, that it's not a pitch
you can hit on your first time at bat.
It's strange.
Kyoshiro is more of the type that swings
on the first pitch if it's in the zone.
Here I go!
W-What?
Was he waiting... For the high-speed slider?
I can't believe it!
My high-speed slider... With just one pitch?
Second batter, second baseman, Taniguchi.
That was a fluke!
That was definitely a fluke!
He took off!
He completely read the pitcher's motion.
That was clever.
How many times do you think I'm going to let you do that!?
Safe!
And I was on the lookout...
What a runner!
What's the battery doing? Get a grip!
Calm down! It's not as if the run has already been given up.
I'll hold them off from now on, so there's no problem...
Using my high-speed slider!
Easy!
Good! We have the lead!
My pitching isn't working.
Katori...
Shit! He's completely caught up in the moment.
Don't mind, don't mind! It's only four runs!
It's already over.
Huh? What's over?
He's completely overwhelmed by the aura of
the Japanese team. He can't pitch normally.
And for a batter, there's no easier prey than a scared pitcher.
Remember that, junior.
Is this the right time to talk about that?
You're on the same team, so the least
you could do is encourage him!
What?
As usual, you're ignoring the proper way to address your elders, kid!
Don't call me a kid! There's only a year's difference
in age between you and me, old man!
Come on, stop it! The game is still going on!
Akutsu, go to the bullpen and warm up your arm.
Ah... Y-Yes!
As I though, they're one step above us.
Was it too much for rookies to face the Japanese representatives?
Give it all you've got!
But if it starts to look bad, give up the mound to me right away!
Shut up! Don't say that, even if you're joking!
Katori is a good pitcher.
The nine victories he gained as a rookie
last year were the real thing.
If his pitching got thrown out of rhythm...
It's because of that slider that got hit.
By hitting the pitch Katori was most confident in,
he crushed any chance Katori might've had.
And with the way he ran through us, he
completely snatched the flow of the game.
Ball! Ball four!
Shit!
Good, good.
In spite of his four-run lead, he won't relax
or ask for anything but small plays.
So this is Coach Sasaki's baseball?
Damn! I want to get onto that mound and fight!
Ball! Ball four!
One out and bases loaded, huh?
I'm sorry. I aimed too much for the corner.
Don't worry. This game has only just begun.
Le'ts just concentrate on preventing the next run.
Yeah, it's just four runs. We'll get you double that.
All right.
Ninth batter, shortstop, Yamazaki.
Second! You still have time!
Out!
We're not out of it yet! It's just the beginning!
Coming back from a four-run deficit is easy!
Strike! Batter out!
That pitcher's completely revved up.
Yeah, even though they're stronger individually,
I thought there'd be gaps we could take advantage
of in their lack of cohesion early in the game.
But it looks like it won't be that simple.
I agree.
And they still have a lot of spare energy.
Ignoring that last offensive, it feels like their
entire team is moving around as one.
Coach Sasaki's aim: small ball, eh?
It just means it has matured that much.
This is a strong team.
It looks like it could become a tough game.
Toshi...
Don't tell me you've already given up.
Of course not!
I'm just mentioning how much it's worth playing!
For Young Japan, replacing the pitcher Katori for Akutsu.
Coach!
I'm going to warm up in the bullpen.
Whenever it starts looking risky, please call me out!
Sure...
Now that I'm here, we're not going to give up any more runs!
First batter, right fielder, Kyoshiro.
You better hold him off nice and proper. Giving
up any more runs will make it really tough.
Like I'd let him hit that easily!
A knuckleball on the first pitch...
Don't think of small ball as baseball that utilizes small tricks.
If you see an opportunity, it's about going all-out after it.
The small ball strategy is to play impeccable baseball.
What the heck is he doing, throwing such a careless pitch.
I'm the relief pitcher for the Arrows!
Why am I intiminated by the title "Japanese representative"?
Ball! Ball four!
I-It's no good.
Don't force it, Akutsu.
Shit!
First batter, right fielder, Kyoshiro.
One out and the bases loaded. Akutsu
just isn't good enough today, is he?
This is as far as it goes.
Umpire!
Who will it be?
For Young Japan, replacing the pitcher Akutsu,
Shigeno.
All right, let's go!
G-Goro?
Oh, so he's already been allowed to come out.
Is this the rookie you taught to throw forkballs, Suguro?
Yeah. But I really just gave him a few pointers, you know.
You're here earlier than I thought you'd be.
Yeah. Everything worked out like I hoped.
I'll just retire Kyoshiro and shut out the Japanese national team.
You take care of that lead with come-from-behind
home runs until we win this game in style.
That's how we're going to get onto the representative team...
And next, we fire up our engines and go to the World Cup, Toshi!
Yeah!
It's been two weeks since I pointed out that lifeless pitch, and
it looks like you've been experimenting with a few things.
Now let's see the answer that you came up with.
Play!
Please, Shigeno...
Change the flow of the game...
Otherwise, we'll look like untalented fools.
Strike!
Hmm... That was fast.
Starting with a pitch outside of the zone.
Looks like he's done some studying.
Foul!
His pitches are moving a lot more than two
weeks ago when his arm wasn't warmed up.
This was the exact same trajectory as before, but
I couldn't make perfect contact in one swing...
Well then... How will you come with the next one?
Good, we've trapped him.
Shigeno...
Will you throw it here?
Here comes my new weapon, the gyrofork!
Great!
Sorry, sorry!
The control isn't there yet, is it?
Shit! We trained so much yesterday
and that's all the control I have!?
With the bases full, the fork is just too risky.
A forkball, Goro!
That was just a mistake.
If it's the same as yesterday's practice, you
should get one on-target every other pitch.
With three pitches to work with, if only one goes on-target,
I'm sure Kyoshiro will swing and miss.
So don't be afraid of throwing wild
pitches, and throw it as hard as you can!
Here it comes!
Foul!
Wasn't that a forkball?
Y-Yeah... When did he learn how to throw such a forkball?
Impossible! How could he even touch that forkball?
Is Kyoshiro's bat control that good?
Anyway, another forkball.
Going head-on with the national team
with only fastballs is too difficult.
If we can take Kyoshiro down with a forkball...
I'll make the batters focus more on that
and make your fastball more dangerous.
He...
He saw through it!
It's not good enough yet.
With control like that, he shouldn't even use it.
No, that's not the only problem...
His forkball has a fatal flaw.
Ball!
So this is your answer?
I'm disappointed.
I see it now. It's the timing of the break.
It starts to drop too soon, so the batter
has time to realize it's a forkball.
We didn't have time to correct that during practice yesterday.
It's too risky, Toshi.
The forkball is no good anymore, so let's
drop it and fight with my fastball.
W-What?!
A forkball!
Kyoshiro already knows that you can't throw anything but fastballs.
But it's better to risk walking in a run than getting a big hit.
Damn!
Goro!
You got hit on your fastball. I won't start
complaining and saying I told you so...
But tell me one thing. Do you trust in my lead or not?
Talk about a load of crap!
I never thought that you had so little faith in my fastball.
Batting second, second baseman, Taniguchi.
What was that about?
You're the one who wanted to throw forkballs.
I'm only doing this because you said that
your fastball wouldn't be enough.
Well for the time being, we have one
out and runners on second and third.
So let's go with a low and inside fastball to avoid a sacrifice fly.
Strike!
T-The opposite side?!
Ball!
A-Again, to the side opposite my glove.
I see... So it's like that, huh?
You bastard.
Well then, throw it wherever you'd like!
You never thought a catcher was any better than a wall, anyway.
Strike!
Huh?!
T-Time!
What an interesting play!
Are you all right?
W-Where the hell were you throwing the ball!?
Sorry, I didn't grip the ball right, and it slipped.
And who would've thought he'd get a jump start against a lefty?
What?!
Maybe you should've attempted to pick him off.
Even if I had thrown that ball accurately,
he probably would have been safe.
So you're saying everything is my fault now?
Huh? No, I didn't mean to say it like that!
In fact, Toshi, you hit me on purpose, didn't you!?
Hey! What're you guys doing?
Anyway, first is open.
We should walk Taniguchi to get to the next batter.
I agree. It'll be easier to defend with the bases loaded.
If it goes well, we might be able to get a double
play and finish without Itao coming to bat.
I disagree!
What's the point of playing a bases-loaded
strategy in a game where we're already behind?
That's exactly my point!
Whatever, Toshiya. You've always been a coward!
You and your probabilities! You can't do
anything but pitch around the batter!
Y-You're the one who's so crude you can't see anything beyond that!
Aren't you the one who gave up a hit by
ignoring my signs in the first place?
What did you say?!
Will you two cut it out?! We're in the middle of a game!
You're taking too long!
If the place that got hit is fine, then let's continue!
Y-Yes!
Sato...
When two childhood friends become pros and form a
battery, their pride is bound to clash at some point.
However...
You're probably the person who knows Shigeno best.
If you can't get him to give you his best, who will?
Play!
I never thought you had such little faith in my fastball.
He's right. I was so preoccupied with making him
use the forkball that I forgot about his strengths.
What? We're facing him?
Knowing that you're easily swayed by your feelings,
getting you in a good mood by letting you throw
your fastball is the first thing I need to do.
Strike! Batter out!
Nice ball!
Damn, that last ball was fast. I was a little worried
about it being a forkball and swung too late.
So he came with a fastball because
he can't use his forkball effectively.
But isn't it a little absurd to come at us with just a fastball?
Wouldn't it be best to substitute him out?
When I told him that his pitches had no life to them,
I didn't mean for him to try to learn breaking balls.
It's true that I hit his fastball easily earlier this spring...
And against the fastball he delivered in this
confusion, it wasn't hard to get a base hit...
But I still feel...
Somewhat frustrated?
In the end, it was just a single.
Strike!
There aren't any pitchers who can
work in Triple A... With only a fastball.
Although we can get hits, it's not easy to get a home run...
Against that powerful fastball of yours.
And that's exactly why I recommended
that you be included in this game.
Strike!
Before relying on something like that hastily-modified
forkball, the first thing you should realized...
Is that you've been overestimating the control that
you've polished so much, and stop relying on it.
Foul! Foul!
Damn, so close!
Seriously?
That pitch was low and on the outside corner!
T-Time!
Goro, did you put everything you had
on that last pitch to strike him out?
Yeah, I don't need to waste pitches.
I'm confident in my control.
What is it?
Goro...
I won't ask for a forkball anymore.
Your fastball is enough, but could
you throw it where I put my glove?
I believe in your fastball, so could you trust in my lead just a little?
All right.
It was never Goro's style to waste pitches...
But he didn't have the control that he has now.
There were the occasional balls, and he even hit a few batters...
As a result, those did the job of wasted pitches.
A pitcher that doesn't do these things intentionally
will never be feared, no matter how fast he is.
Ball!
That's why I told you wasting pitches is useless.
He's the cleanup batter of their team!
The low and away pitch just now was hit
because Yamanaka had nothing to fear.
Since your control was already acknowledged
and seen extensively during batting practice,
he had no reason to back off.
If we don't get rid of that docile perception
of you, we won't be able to hold them back.
We have to brush him back with a pitch that's high and inside, Goro.
Editor's Note: A brushback pitch is a high and inside fastball used to back
the batter off the plate and make him afraid to stand close to the plate.
If we don't use these kinds of tactics, then we won't be able
to take these top-class batters out with only your fastball.
Ball!
That's not good enough! Such an easily-dodged
brushback pitch isn't effective!
A batter of his caliber won't even blink an eye
against a brushback pitch of that level.
Hey, is Sato asking for a brushback pitch
even though he's just a rookie?
That's pretty dirty. What'll he do if someone gets hurt?
Just one more; doesn't matter if it's a ball.
I just want you to scare him enough to make him step back!
Shit!
Dead ball!
A-Are you all right, Yamanaka?
How dare you ask me that, you bastard!
You kept asking for high and inside pitches!
Uh, well...
I never told you to hit him!
Besides, it's not a brushback pitch if it's below the hips.
Toshi...
Are you really asking me to throw such a
dangerous pitch knowing what I've been through?
S-Sorry.
B-But I just thought you overcame that fear.
Of course I did.
I wouldn't have become a pitcher if I was
afraid of throwing above a batter's chest,
but I've never resorted to throwing a brushback pitch
near the head of a batter just to scare them.
Not once!
If I had to resort to this to get someone out,
I would have given up pitching a long time ago.
Even Gibson made a mistake...
And that was just a really unfortunate accident.
There's just no way that I can do
something like that knowing what I know.
I'm sorry.
It was a bit insensitive of me,
but what are we suppose to do next?
The forkball is no good either.
How do you intend to hold the Japanese representatives back?
Maybe it was just too soon for us.
Using a forkball learned overnight...
And a mixture of pitches, wasn't going to hold
down the top Japanese professionals.
The representatives aren't that easy, after all.
Goro...
Batting fourth: left fielder, Itao.
But still...
That doesn't mean we should give up.
Let's end all these unrealistic plans we had of trying to
impress the coaches to get onto the national team...
We'll just be the rookies we are and go all out to show them all!
Yeah!
Play!
Too bad, Minor Leaguer.
You have the spirit of a true challenger,
but your pitches aren't ready to cross swords with the world's.
Low and inside! I've got you now!
Foul!
That ball just now had power!
So he's serious now?
How did he...
Outside?
Foul!
That's it! He stopped caring and something inside him changed!
What's up with him?
Didn't he learn anything from what Kyoshiro or I tried to teach him?
But with the pitch he has, it looks like all the advice we gave
him were just small tricks to him. I gotta admit, he's got guts.
I never thought you'd break two of my bats.
But...
There's no way I'm letting a young Minor Leaguer take me out.
Down the middle? Don't underestimate me!
So you're really going home?
You did notify the manager and the coaches, right?
Yeah.
And next week, spring training camps for the Majors start anyway.
Now that I know that I'm not skilled enough yet,
there's not much point in me staying in Okinawa.
Well, I did find a few things to focus on,
so I'll try to improve on them one by one.
I have to work on that forkball if I want
to be able to follow your lead.
What!?
Goro packed his bags and left?
Yeah. He said, "Thank you again for your
time. It seems that I still lack training."
He's more humble than I thought.
T-That little brat. Again, without a word to his father...
That loud-mouthed Minor Leaguer ran
away with his tail between his legs.
He was only inches away from being knocked out yesterday.
Is that what it looked like to you?
Itao?
The only hit we got was that single from Kyoshiro.
As for me...
I had three bats broken and a long fly ball to center.
No, in any other stadium that one would've been gone.
To hit it that far without hitting it off the
core of the bat; that's Itao for you!
Without hitting it off the core?
There's no doubt that the third pitch hit dead on.
Oh, no...
I thought it was only a sore throat, but it turned out to be a fever.
This is the worst.
Tomorrow is Valentine's Day, and the key person is in Okinawa.
He hasn't even bothered to send me a text message.
Mom, I think I caught a cold. Can you make
me some rice soup or something?
Note: We will come home tomorrow morning. Please eat your meals together with Taiga, all right? Mom and Dad
Oh, that's right. She said they were going to the hot springs today.
There's nothing in here...
And Taiga won't be home until tonight.
There's nothing I can do. The best thing
to do is probably to go back to bed.
Ah! And now I have the chills!
Yes?
Y-Yes?
Honda!?
What the heck are you doing?
I'm surprised you're here! What happened with the camp?
Well, I went all out, but in the end,
it wasn't as easy as I thought it would be.
Now I know that I'm not good enough
to be on the national team yet.
That's why I left the camp.
I... I see.
Besides, spring training for the Majors starts next week.
To minimize jet lag, I was thinking of
leaving Japan the day after tomorrow.
T-The day after tomorrow!?
Y-Yeah...
That's why I came to spend some time with you
today, but you had to go and catch a cold.
S-So I guess you shouldn't stay here too long.
It'd be terrible if you caught my cold
just before going back to America.
Yeah, I guess you're right.
It's really too risky.
Well then, I'm off.
Take care!
You cold-hearted rat!
Woah, it's still rising.
Well, I did suggest that he should go, but I didn't
mean that he should leave so quickly.
And we won't see each other for a while once he's back in America.
Does he really love me?
Taiga?
Hey, Shimizu!
H-Honda!?
Here you go. I bought you some fruit and other stuff.
Hon-da?
I must have dozed off!
Thank you.
I feel much better.
I think my temperature went down,
and I'd feel bad if you caught my cold, so you should go now.
Nope, your fever hasn't gone down at all.
I'll stay with you until Taiga comes home.
Don't worry about me. I don't catch colds easily.
I'll go change that towel.
I'm telling you it's fine!
You know we can only be together for this little while.
H-Honda!
What are you doing? Get back to bed!
I-It's decided!
I'm going to America!
WHAT?!
Please, Mom! Please say yes!
No! It's far too dangerous for a young
woman to go to America alone.
I'll be fine! I know someone there, so I won't be alone!
You know someone?
Oh, I get it!
You want to go there to see Shigeno!
He had to say something...
Shigeno? What's this about Shigeno?
Oh, you didn't know, Mom?
Those two have already started down
the path of a serious relationship.
Don't use that tone of voice to make it sound so dirty!
Come to think of it... Isn't Shigeno trying
to become a Major Leaguer in America?
Yeah...
Since he's trying really hard over there,
I wanted to go and give him my support.
Well, there won't be any problems if she's with him, Mom,
but I don't think Dad would be too happy if
you told him that she's going to see a guy.
I guess it can't be helped, then.
Eh?
I'll just tell your dad that you're going with a friend.
Just make sure you don't cause any trouble for Shigeno.
Thank you, Mom!
In America, renting a car is supposed to
be safe and give you the most mobility,
and I got my driver's license a year ago, but...
Editor's Note: A paper driver is someone who has a driver's license, but outside
of taking the exam, they have no experience driving on a day-to-day basis.
I'm a total paper driver!
I'm worn out.
But I did drive a long way since I left the airport
in Miami, so only a little more to go, eh?
Traveling overseas alone is actually
easier than I thought it would be!
All right, then! Let's go!
N-No way!
Why is the engine not starting!? Is the battery dead!?
What should I do? I could laugh at how deserted it is...
Excuse me!
Wait, no.
Who knows what would happen to a cute girl
like me if I got picked up by a total stranger!
All right! If it's like this, all I can do is to walk
to a place where there's bound to be a phone!
Maybe I should have gone in the other direction.
I've been walking for over an hour, and
there's still nothing to be seen!
And the sun's also setting. This is like a really bad joke.
Please let there be something on the other side of this hill.
Yes! Yes!
Thank God!
I knew you couldn't be that cruel to a poor girl
like me who just arrived in a foreign country.
I can't believe it...
It's over...
I'll just waste away just like this abandoned hotel.
Help! Help!
Please don't hurt me and let me live!
Hey! Hey, Shimizu!
What the heck are you doing here?
H-Honda?
What happened to your car?
I-It broke down.
But what're you doing here?
You said you'd be arriving around five, but it was getting late,
so we decided to look for you on the road you'd probably take.
Come on, get up.
You're late! What would you have done if someone attacked me!?
No, I was never worried about that.
How dare you!
It should work now. Try to start the engine.
He says to try and start the engine.
Wow, it started!
Thank you!
Thank you, Mister... Uh...?
Keane.
Thanks for doing this, Keane.
Don't mention it.
He's not really a friendly person... Is he a teammate?
Yes. It's his off-season now, but he already has a
contract in the Majors and is a full-time starter.
Man, I really thought it was the end of me!
No matter how far I walked, there were no
stores, and then it started to get dark.
You're a nuisance right from the start, eh?
I didn't come here for a vacation, you know.
H-Honda, have you had dinner yet?
How could I with all the trouble you've caused?
I have a game tomorrow, and I'm very busy,
so could you hurry up and get me back to the dorm?
Will you stop nagging already!?
It's not my fault the battery died!
Besides, when your girlfriend comes
all the way to America to see you,
shouldn't you be at least a little happy?
Shimizu! Keep your eyes on the road!
Oh my God!
Wow!
You have a great place, you can see the ocean from here!
Oh! Excuse my intrusion!
And now to add this...
Honda, Honda.
Yeah?
It's almost ready. I'm sure it's been a while
since you've had a Japanese meal, right?
You must be looking forward to it.
Is curry really a Japanese meal?
If you start complaining, I won't let you have any!
Fine, fine...
Curry?!
Here you go!
Hmm?
That's strange...
Bon apptit!
What're you doing, Honda?
You didn't leave any apples uncut!
Why would I do that!?
Well, what do you think?
Do you think you can make it in the Majors?
Hmm... It's hard to say, but for now, I've been lucky
enough not to have been sent back to the Minors.
I see...
Oh, right!
Here's the phone number for this place.
Give me a call when you've checked
in and gotten settled at your hotel.
Hotel? Oh, right. I didn't tell you...
I spent almost everything I had on renting a car,
so I was hoping that you'd let me crash here...
Huh!?
No, no, I refuse! I'm not going anywhere!
It won't work! There are plenty of cheap
motels around here, so leave already!
What's the big deal? I'll sleep on the couch
and I won't cause any problems!
Don't you know how expensive hotels are?
Cut it out already!
H-Honda?
I told you that I'm not here on vacation.
So far, I've only been used for middle relief, but
tomorrow they're trying me out as a starter.
It really is an important day for me.
This dorm was completely full at the beginning of spring training,
but now it's almost empty since over half of
the occupants were sent back to the Minors.
The same goes for me, too. If I give up hits
tomorrow, I won't be able to stay here, either.
Everyone here is in the middle of a
fight to claim a spot in the Majors,
and none of them have their girlfriends with them! None of them!
I'm sorry.
I knew you were in the middle of a difficult challenge, but...
It's just that when you came back from
Okinawa, you left right away for America.
And you don't call me very often, either.
It's like you're not letting me get closer, to the
point when you're always looking for a fight.
I knew I was being selfish...
I knew, but...
I couldn't just do nothing and wait another year!
I'm not that strong!
Shimizu!
I'm sorry.
I was giving you the could shoulder.
You may think this is funny because it sounds old-fashioned,
but I think that a man and woman shouldn't take the
idea of spending a night under the same roof lightly.
With a person whom I really love, it's
something I don't want to take lightly.
I'm really sorry.
I understand. It's all right.
I'm relieved.
Oh, no!
I can't believe it's two o'clock! I overslept because of the jet lag!
Ah! He said he would be the starting pitcher today!
Eh?
That's not Honda.
What does that mean?
Huh, he's already given up six runs!?
Maybe they took him out...
Out!
That must be it...
I guess even for Honda, getting to the Majors isn't easy.
Hey, Shigeno! We're counting on your
sharp pitching for this inning, too!
Shigeno?
Ah, I got it wrong!
That's right! He plays for the Hornets!
On top of that, he has a no-hitter going into the fifth!
Strike out!
Great, Shigeno!
Six innings and no hits! That's amazing!
But why'd they take you out?
I was hoping for a perfect game.
Well, it was just an exhibition game, so it
wouldn't have meant anything, anyway.
Anyway, that's good enough, right?
With that, your promotion is almost certain, right?
Not exactly...
Today's opponents were poor at batting,
so it's important to get good results in the next game.
But I'm relieved!
At least I didn't get demoted to the Minors with you watching.
That would have been too lame.
By the way, tomorrow we have a day off, so I have free time.
Do you want to go somewhere?
Yes, let's!
Ah! That was refreshing!
Hello?
Shigeno? It's Stacey.
Boss!
I'm sorry to call so late, but it's an emergency.
I need you to pack your things tonight and
take the next flight to Los Angeles.
I'm afraid we'll have to postpone your
promotion to the Majors for now.
D-Does that mean you're sending me to a Minor League camp, Boss?
Of course not!
How could I justify sending a guy who just
pitched six perfect innings back to the Minors?
Don't worry. It's not a Minor League camp.
Well then why do I have to go to LA?
Have I been traded or something?
You'll find out when you get there. I'm
sure it'll be a great experience for you.
We've arrived, sir.
Isn't this just a Minor League stadium?
What's so good about this place?
Here you are!
It's been a while, Goro.
F-Father! What are you doing here?
What? What do you mean "What?"
Wasn't it obvious once you saw this?
No, I don't understand...
Sheesh! Can't you watch the news once in a while?
The Japanese team advanced past the first round
of the Asian preliminaries in first place,
so we're here for the second round, which takes place here.
S-So what am I doing here?
You're going to love this, Goro!
You've been selected for the Japanese national team!
You're going to replace Suguro, who retired after getting injured.
W-What!?